## Ivan Lamden

ivan.lamden@gmail.com

https://linktr.ee/i1d

## **Professional profile**

I am an experienced IT professional with over 10 years of experience in the industry. Have an "IT intuition" that helps me quickly understand any software product. Able to coordinate teams, build partnerships, and work collaboratively with engineers, vendors, and business teams to ensure successful completion of a project. Flexible to work in both fast and slow-paced environments. Currently, I'm studying at the Geekbrains University aiming to switch the domain to the AI/ML.

### **Achievements**

Hyundai Glovis — employee of the year (2018, 2019).

Geekbrains University — teachers assistant from January 2022 (volunteering).

## Work experience

IT manager at Hyundai Glovis Rus LLC, St. Petersburg

January 2013 — Present

- Deliver uninterruptible IT services to the internal and external clients;
- Managing, planning, coordination, mentoring of the IT team members;
- Providing optimal technical equipment in the field of IT according to business needs;
- Strategic planning of the IT team;
- Built dedicated Helpdesk team to provision smooth support for company's employees;
- Budgeting, tenders, contractual work;
- Constant improving of the company's infrastructure to save employee's time on waiting the system to load;
- Hiring manager for IT candidates in St. Petersburg and Moscow;
- User support and education.

#### Senior IT specialist at Hyundai Glovis Rus LLC, St. Petersburg

July 2011 — January 2013

- Oracle DB administration (Solaris) of all databases (3 production), monitoring, performance tuning, backups, recovery;
- Supporting and developing warehouse management system (~400 users, ~133 simultaneously) (Trustform, JSP, SQL, PL/SQL, CI/CD);
- User support and education;
- Implementation of project management systems (Redmine);
- General setup of Motorola PDAs;
- Selecting and purchasing necessary equipment;
- Interviewing candidates for IT for branches in St. Petersburg and Moscow;

Equipment installation including installation using a hydraulic lift.

# Deputy Manager of System Design department at Petrocard CJSC, St. Petersburg January 2009 — July 2011

- Oracle DB administration (Windows, AIX), monitoring, performance tuning, backups, recovery;
- support of online and offline data processing systems, user support and education;
- communicating with VISA and MasterCard regarding dispute transactions;
- analytical statistics calculating;
- verification of reports of online and offline data processing systems.

## **Education**

Geekbrains University, St. Petersburg https://gb.ru/		
AI / ML September 2020 — Present		
ITMO University, St. Petersburg <a href="https://en.itmo.ru/">https://en.itmo.ru/</a>		
Master's degree, Applied Mathematics and Informatics September 2007 — June 2009	Bachelor's degree, Applied Mathematics and Informatics September 2003 — June 2007	
Diploma thesis: "Computational environment development based on text decomposition".	Diploma thesis: "Fluid flow simulation in a 2D-channel with an impediment".	
Result: C++ app.	Result: C++ app for visual fluid flow simulation.	

## Languages

Russian	English
Native speaker	C1

## **Courses / Certificates**

Python Developer, hyperskill.org  June 2020 — Present	AWS EC2 workshop, Amazon Luxembourg December 2012
Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations Associate February 2022	Oracle 11g DBA I, FORS Training Center June 2009
Al for Earth Monitoring, EUMETSAT / futurelearn.com October 2021 — January 2022	Oracle 11g DBA II, FORS Training Center June 2009
Al for everyone, Coursera July 2020	Oracle 11g Data Guard, FORS Training Center June 2009
The formula to work with people, stratoplan.ru March 2015	Oracle 11g Performance Tuning, FORS Training Center June 2009